Often your password will be stored as a fixed hash value or digest.
So that the system can tell if your password
matches without the password itself ever being visible.
A more secure password with alphanumeric and special characters
will generate a different type of hash digest.
However, this system of password management is already becoming obsolete.
Often for security purposes,
you will be asked to generate a new password
with a minimum number of characters and the software
behind it will recognize the hash function and tell
you if the password is sufficiently secure to be used
or it will prompt you to create a better password.
Attackers can use password hashes to guess your password offline.
If an attacker can copy the password file,
which is usually hashed from a compromised workstation or server
and they know the algorithm that is used to hash the password,
they can use a computer to try random sequences of letters
and number combinations to try to match the known password hash.